ALL CHARACTERS, LOCATIONS,
ORGANIZATIONS, RELIGIONS,
EVENTS, AND OCCUPATIONS
IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS
Seo-yoon, I'm home.
Your mom?
The call cannot be connected…
Is something going on outside?
This?
It's dangerous if people attack us.
My mom isn't answering her phone.
We even texted earlier.
MOM: DID YOU EAT?
It must be the base station.
You can call her later.
And even if people knock,
never open the door for them.
I'll be back soon,
so stay here and watch TV.
The TV doesn't work, either.
What?
OFF-AIR NOTICE
DO NOT MOVE AND WAIT FOR THE RESCUE TEAM
That's enough. Come here.
We should completely block it.
You saw how they were before.
Go over there and get some rest.
Jung-kook.
Keep an eye on him.
Okay.
Don't look this way. Face the wall.
What is it?
The infected are out there.
It's too quiet.
Hey! Face the wall!
What's all this?
Mister, what do you think you're doing?
Why isn't it working?
I had more than 1,000 viewers online!
- Dong-hyun.
- What?
The symptoms of this Mad Human Disease…
Are they like, a pounding heart,
the scratch mark getting itchy and hot,
and things like that?
That's menopause.
What are they doing?
Why aren't they working?
Where is the Management Office?
Which building was it, again?
It's next to the children's library.
Forget it. I'll go find it.
Dong-hyun!
I'm telling you, it's menopause.
It's the truth! Can't you believe me?
This is absolutely unbelievable.
I'm telling you,
everyone in other buildings got infected.
Their eyes rolled up into their heads
and they latched onto things like this!
What are you doing?
Will my kids…
be okay?
They'll be doing better than us, at least!
Old lady, you live in Unit 401, right?
Is the Internet not working
at your house, either?
I'm not old, and…
Neither the Internet
nor our phones are working.
Did you hear all the other
building residents got infected?
Really?
That's crazy. Who said that?
An announcement?
He said that. Ask him.
It's true, I mean it.
What is this?
Excuse me.
Don't stay here. Go to the gym.
Okay? Everyone is there.
What do you mean by "everyone"?
The residents.
Can you see it?
Is this real blood?
Then do you think this is ketchup?
- I wasn't the only one who saw it, either.
- I saw it too.
Mr. Lee at the Management Office
got infected,
and his eyes turned white,
and he did this…
It's just that I don't understand.
The other buildings were saying
our building had to be blocked off.
But they all got infected already?
That makes no sense!
Hi.
Is this real blood? Whose blood is it?
Put your phone down.
We need to talk for a moment.
- Is this blood?
- Is this really blood?
Stop recording. Come out.
It's real blood.
You're trying to scare me, aren't you?
What are you talking about?
Are you trying to scare me away
to become the resident representative?
It must be a prank by the kids.
Building representative…
How do we open this thing?
Dong-hyun, do you know how to open this?
I don't care about being
the representative, so don't worry.
Stand back. It's dangerous.
- It's just…
- You shouldn't go outside.
It won't take long.
I think I saw someone…
Can't you see this?
- You don't know what's out there.
- We're all curious.
- Please calm down.
- Just open half of it.
- We're frustrated, that's why!
- Put your phone down!
- And calm down.
- Wait.
I said, stand back.
Where are you going?
They want to open the door.
You saw that monster earlier.
Then you should stop them, not run away.
Sae-bom, you came just in time.
Tell them what's out there.
You scared me.
It's open.
If you want to go out, then go.
Not like that…
Go on out.
The air in the basement floor is stuffy.
It's not a great place to smoke.
How could you give in so quickly?
Fine.
I will trust you two, just this once.
Detective.
I don't have to worry about it, right?
We must tell the other residents as well.
We need to discuss food matters
and basic provisions for non-residents.
We can't make announcements now,
and the Internet is down too.
How would we do that?
You can tell them yourself.
Where's your gun?
I gave it to Jung-kook.
What did the man downstairs say
when he cuffed you?
Personal liberty is an important right
guaranteed by the Constitution.
He can't do that without
a proper legal process.
I don't really remember what he said.
He didn't say much, but I don't think
he told me about my rights.
Then do the police have the evidence?
By any chance…
are you thinking that
I killed my wife or something like that?
It doesn't matter what I think.
It's up to the judiciary
to make the judgment.
It's just…
I loved my wife, Min-ji,
with all of my heart.
I still can't believe that she's dead.
Then the defending strategy should be
the wrongful arrest of an innocent man.
There's also a dermatology clinic
under my wife's name,
and I'm also curious about
how the issues of management
and inheritance would go.
Okay.
You must have
that murder charge lifted first.
Excuse me.
They said everyone should come to the gym.
I'll go out first, so cover me.
Let's switch.
I'm better with the bat than you are.
But you were a pitcher.
If I hadn't injured my leg,
I'd be a Major Leaguer by now.
Here we go.
- Where did everyone go?
- I'm sure they went home.
The infected turn back
to normal after some time.
What would they think
when they see what they've done?
I'm sure they'd regret it.
And they won't be able
to admit what they did.
Yes. I'm sure they would want
to go home and clean up.
There were traces
of an attempt to wipe off
the bloodstain on the door.
It means they wanted
to erase what they did.
And they want to hide the fact
that they want to drink blood.
I didn't do it.
I only took a look.
LIEUTENANT COLONEL HAN TAE-SEOK
I should've asked for a walkie-talkie.
What do you think is going on outside?
There's a high chance of chaos
with lots of the infected pouring out.
- Or…
- Or?
Or they gave up on this place.
We tried to arrest
the Next dealers all at once,
but they noticed
and locked the door from inside.
- How many?
- About 50.
They were having
an exclusive party for members.
We can unlock it within five minutes.
Turn the music off.
Shut down all the power inside the club.
Don't open the door. Block them all.
Send out everyone from the other floors
and lock the building down.
Go and lock the building down.
If you need any, you can take some.
You're suddenly in a good mood.
Everyone outside is infected.
And that's a good thing?
Because I don't have to go to prison.
I just need to find
a way to lift my false charges.
You must have a plan.
We just need to silence
the couple downstairs.
I have to persuade them
before the lockdown is lifted.
And you are
on my side anyway, right?
Do I have to go too?
A lawyer should show up
at times like this.
Honey, they said our units are fine.
It's not because I'm scared! Come on.
I just can't believe that
everyone outside is infected.
You must be very scared.
Heading to the meeting?
I'm not scared of the infected at all.
The residents aren't going to
like you very much.
I'm sure many are thinking
that you caused this lockdown.
I told you, I'm innocent.
Where's Ms. Woo?
Sang-hee cares about
what others think of her,
like Mr. Lawyer here.
UNDER MAINTENANCE
Gosh.
Ma'am.
Ma'am, is something out there?
No.
You fell quite hard that day.
Did you go to the hospital?
I'm okay…
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Isn't she the one who bumped
into the woman next door?
Yes, Unit 302.
Don't go near her.
You might get infected.
I won't get infected.
Dad, what are you doing?
Damn it!
You should go out
and find out what's going on
even if it's dangerous out there.
Are you just going to sit here?
The Internet is still out too.
Hurry up! Come here!
- You…
- Sir.
I told you that it's dangerous outside.
All the other building residents
are infected.
Damn it! This is so frustrating!
What is she doing here?
Why did you come all the way here?
You said you were tired.
Mom, are you sick?
I'm not sick…
I'm just a bit tired, that's all.
I saw the bloodstains,
but is it really full of patients outside?
There are a lot of witnesses.
See?
"Do not move."
Who are the witnesses?
Who saw that the outside
was filled with the infected?
Me. I saw them.
Anyone from the higher floors?
No public rentals, you mean?
I'm asking just in case there are those
who can make more logical judgments.
Excuse me.
Who are you to doubt
my brother's judgment?
My brother works at a company.
He's a manager there.
Yes, and I'm a lawyer.
My job is to figure out
if the testimony can serve as evidence.
You promote yourself in the apartments
without an office, right?
You were advertising yourself
in the apartment elevator.
It's not promotion. I'm accepting cases.
Don't you know
what "accepting cases" mean?
I write novels, you know.
What's your signature work?
- Love Under Joint Name.
- Calm down, everyone.
Calm down.
Yes, good.
I know you're all sensitive now,
but we shouldn't be fighting
among ourselves.
I didn’t see any infected either,
but you're all saying the same thing…
I'll give you money.
If any of you figure out
what's happening outside…
It's not much,
but I'll give you 200,000 won.
If they really are outside,
we should stay inside.
And we can share the food
until the situation is clear.
If you're not going outside,
then okay, sure.
I will give you…
a total of 300,000 won in cash.
What a troll.
- Did you search everywhere?
- It's safe here.
Then can we start operating
the elevator again?
Sure, go ahead.
By the way, ma'am.
If I were you,
I wouldn't take the elevator.
You can't escape if you find
someone infected in a small space.
I believe I told you to stay home.
Why?
You're supposed to release him 48 hours
after arresting him without a warrant.
Does everyone know
that you're a murderer, Mr. Oh?
You're atrocious.
Do you have any witnesses?
Some of you saw my wife
wandering around, right?
I called an ambulance
and took her outside.
I do admit that I couldn't protect
my wife until the end.
My heart breaks the most!
Is failing to protect my wife
until the end such a big crime?
And there's the presumption
of innocence too.
You must be glad
the apartments are in lockdown.
Don't worry,
I'm going to stay here anyway.
And this place is
no different from jail, anyway.
Mister, you got something here.
Don't even think about doing anything
to that lady staying with you.
Because I'll kill you if you do.
What are you saying?
You're so unsophisticated.
Ridiculous.
Let's go.
Please be with all families
suffering due to death
- and let them find peace from you, Lord.
- You're here.
- We pray in Jesus' name. Amen.
- Amen.
Oh Joo-hyung recruited
those who'd go outside with him.
People want to go outside?
He said he'd pay them 300,000.
I was tempted too, to be honest.
Three hundred thousand.
I said it's dangerous at night,
so it was postponed to tomorrow morning.
Then what about today?
We have to decide on food
and places to sleep for visitors.
Those who are visiting from outside…
If you need food, please come to Unit 401.
I'll give you instant noodles and water.
Me too. Unit 602.
Do you have clothes to change into too?
People offered to chip in.
It seems that some people are still kind.
What about Oh Joo-hyung?
Don't even mention him.
He said there's no food at home,
so he has nothing to share.
I was stupid for asking.
Bye.
By the way, why aren't you going outside?
It seemed like you didn't believe
it was filled with the infected outside.
It'd be good to go outside
with the others and check.
I have a professional job.
I can't go with only that much money.
Then I'll give you a million
without any withholding tax.
How about that?
Mr. Oh, you must stop
taunting people with money.
Let's go. Now.
Okay, goodbye. Go get some rest.
What does that bastard take me for?
Why did you stop me?
I was about to kill him right away.
Honey, it's no good to be involved
with a lunatic like that.
Maybe we should just drop this case.
Also, there's a dermatology clinic
under my wife's name,
and I'm also curious about
how the issues of management…
That jerk…
We can just send him to prison
if necessary.
We just need to make money.
MY WIFE
I'M DOING FINE, DON’T WORRY
- I wonder if this would be enough.
- It's heavy.
Yes. Thank you so much.
We will clean this place
before we get out.
No, I live alone, so my house is clean.
- Don't worry, and go get some rest.
- Okay, thank you so much.
Thank you for the food.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Why did you do that earlier?
What?
You defended me.
I'm the only one who can insult you.
It gets on my nerves if someone else does.
Right? We're family after all.
Yes, but you can’t live here.
She's so harsh.
I'M WITH HYUN-KYUNG
LET'S GET A DOG WHEN WE LIVE HERE
Where were you trying to go?
I'm sure you knew
you can’t get out of the apartment.
I told you.
I really did leave something in the car.
- Did you drink water?
- The drug?
I didn't!
I seriously don't know
anything about that.
Oh, my gosh!
Why did you do that?
You're avoiding eye contact,
so you're definitely hiding something.
To be honest…
I am hiding something, but…
it really has nothing to do with you two.
You did drink it.
But humans can't survive
without drinking water,
right?
Clip your fingernails short.
I'll check them tomorrow.
If you tell us who bought the drugs,
we'll find a way for you
to be more comfortable here.
When I get out of here,
I'll report you two.
I mean it.
Do anything you want
if you get out of here safely.
Think wisely.
Looks good.
All right.
Check the expiration date.
Seriously, what's with you?
I'm sure they won't be expired.
Don't you take that off even when you eat?
Stop that, seriously!
Hi.
I'm sorry, but could she stay with you
for the time being?
The cleaners' dorm
is in the basement parking lot,
but she said she's scared
to go down there.
Yes, of course.
That's great.
Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- Okay, bye.
- Please sit here.
- Welcome.
We were just about to eat instant noodles.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Slow down. It's hot.
Today was a long day too.
What about tomorrow?
Shouldn't we stop them from going outside?
How?
Should we block the entrance
and fight them?
Then they'll go through the basement.
We can't do that on our own.
It would be better
to just stay here for one week.
We have food.
And the infected won't break
through the metal gates, either.
What if this doesn't end
even after one week?
Then we should save on food.
Don't tell this to Seo-yoon.
It won't do any good
to make her worry even more.
Okay.
Is it true that it's filled with
Mad Human Disease patients outside?
What?
It's a different building,
not our building.
But it's only in our apartment complex.
Everywhere else is fine.
Was that supposed to be a secret?
You should've told me.
Jung-kook, I have something to tell you.
Come with me.
I…
When telecommunications are fixed,
you can call your mom again,
so you just need to stay here quietly
and leave when the rescue team comes.
Everyone will get better when
the vaccine and the cure are out,
so let's just wait a bit more, okay?
I'm okay.
I'm not injured,
and since it's safer outside,
Mom and Dad must be
doing well outside too.
Of course.
- Right.
- Seo-yoon?
I LOVE YOU TOO, MOM.
MOM, PLEASE CALL ME. MOM?
Mad Human Disease virus,
the so-called Lytta Virus,
is a neurotropic virus similar to rabies.
It moves through the central
nervous system and works in the brain.
It infects the host through
direct contact with blood vessels,
and the symptoms do not occur
until it enters the brain.
It seems that the infected
attack the neck most of the time
to shorten the time it takes
to make it to the brain.
Is it okay as long as we don't get bitten?
As of now,
there are three methods of infection.
Either you get bitten,
get scratched, or take Next.
It is presumed that the infection started
from among those who took Next.
What about the development of the cure?
The problem is, the brain is the
most important organ in the human body,
so it's protected by the BBB,
the blood-brain barrier.
Even if we develop the cure,
it can't enter the brain.
So, are you saying it's impossible?
The lab is now studying
the formation of new antibodies
that work directly on the brain
with an attenuated virus
cultivated at the lab,
so we'll come up with something
within a month.
Can we withhold until then?
It is considered possible, as of now.
But…
If we give up on active cohort isolation
and the infected count exceeds
a certain number, we'll be done for
within 72 hours,
or within one week at the max.
PROGRESS OF CONFIRMED CASES
OF LYTTA VIRUS INFECTION IN KOREA
Go on.
You know that
the lab cultivation is hopeless.
Everyone in the lab died
without antibodies being formed.
Then I should have told them
that the cure cannot be developed?
If we told them that we need
more time and budget…
Then they would have tried to kill
everyone infected.
If the number of the infected
grows without a cure,
then the only solution is
to kill them all.
I thought…
you didn't think of the infected
as human beings, either.
Those who bit and killed people
should be responsible
for what they have done,
don't you think?
We must buy time.
We have to expand
the areas of lockdown, if necessary.
If we want to save more lives…
that's the only way now.
And while we do that,
we must wait for the answer.
PERSONNEL RECORD CARD: YOON SAE-BOM
It's still out.
YOU SHOULD BE HAPPY TOO, MOM
I even told her that
I had to do something about this.
Yi-hyun.
What is that?
A catcher's mask.
Is Seo-yoon still asleep?
We're police officers with public power,
so we can't just sit still.
Hey, we're in quarantine too.
And we're not here
because we're police officers,
and this won't raise our salary, either.
That's true, but…
I'm sure there are those who are
not infected in other buildings too.
We must find a way to save them.
You should think of your own survival.
You can't even run
because of your knee injury.
I'm still faster than old men.
I'll be back soon, so wait.
- Hey!
- You'll wake her.
Good morning.
Seo-yoon, just stay in bed.
You won't grow taller
if you get up right away. Stay in bed.
Aren't you coming?
No, I don't go to dangerous places
because they're dangerous.
Okay…
Hey, you're going to have to
go through me first.
Is it me or the residents?
Good grief, seriously…
There's nothing out there.
Everyone's mistaken.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Think of our kids.
If we get hurt, it won't count
as an industrial accident.
Everyone.
Please remember. Safety comes first, okay?
I heard that your wife passed away.
May she rest in peace.
Thank you.
Give us money too.
But you said the infected are out there.
Yes, and since I'm paid by the government,
I should lead everyone.
I hope you choke on money.
And some for Yi-hyun.
Are you going to take it?
No, thank you.
I don't like your behavior today.
Sorry.
You just violated
the Improper Solicitation and Graft Act.
Can you put this on?
From now on, I will lead this group.
Once you go outside, please be quiet.
Why should we follow your orders?
Because I'm sure you don't want to die.
Lord, please protect those
who are worried and sad about the disease,
and cure those who are ill.
Please comfort the families
grieving death,
- and…
- Amen.
You're being noisy! Stop it already!
Don't touch me. Lord…
What did you just blabber about?
I said, don't touch me!
Has she gone mad?
Good grief.
Where are you going?
Hey!
That little…
This household is a total mess!
Be careful!
There really is no one out here.
Maybe they all left without us.
Hi.
I want to help too.
So you can record
and upload another video?
I will get permission before I upload it.
I promise.
Hi.
Let's hurry.
Follow me.
Are you all okay?
I heard you were infected.
There were some internal problems.
A possibly infected person
was found during a meeting,
so we locked them up
in the children's library.
Wasn't there one in your building too?
Is that person okay?
Did the condition worsen by any chance?
Mister.
Don't you remember me?
Of course, I do.
You aimed a gun at me yesterday morning.
No, after that.
Then is everyone safe
except for the infected
in the children's library?
Yes, we told them to just stay home.
And a few of us will be in charge
of outer communication.
Mister! Stop recording, will you?
Then you didn't get boxed lunches?
We've been waiting, but they didn't come.
It looks like something
happened outside too.
Excuse me, is anyone out there?
Honey.
Are you going to stay here?
- Yes.
- Then keep waiting.
We should get going now.
What are they doing there?
They want to go outside.
They're afraid that the disease
will occur again.
And if they can't resist their thirst,
they will look for more victims.
What should we do now?
The supermarket.
We have to have as much food as possible.
Are you really infected with that
Mad Human Disease or something?
I am not.
You used to smoke marijuana
when you were in the US too.
- You still haven't broken that habit?
- It's not that!
You little punk!
I brought you here
to get closer to the residents,
and you take drugs! You asshole.
Yeon-ok.
Hey.
Don't act like you know me from now on.
Is it really dangerous outside?
If I were you, I would never go outside.
I only have a bunch of useless losers…
If I were you,
I wouldn't take the elevator.
You can't escape if you find
someone infected in a small space.
That's ridiculous.
How can a human being
suddenly change like that…
Ma'am, please open the door!
There are patients
in other buildings right now!
- Really?
- Yes, hurry.
I brought news from outside too.
It's crazy out there.
Okay.
By the way, are you injured?
Your neck, I mean.
I got scratched a bit.
Open the door first.
Wait.
There are symptoms
that show before the disease occurs.
The infected feel extreme thirst.
And they also show compulsive behaviors
like hitting the wall
when they're alone in an empty space.
Are you…
thirsty?
Those people seemed a bit weird,
but they didn’t look ill.
Should we have just
waited for boxed lunches too?
You can go and wait for them.
- Let's go get food first.
- Okay.
Get more water than food.
But how do we pay for this?
You grew up to become
more righteous than I thought.
That's not what it is.
What do you mean? That's what it is.
No, I'm just trying to stick
to the rules as best as I can.
I feel like if I cross the line once,
then the line might move by itself.
Right.
Okay, sir.
You're very pure and clean.
Like Type 1 water. So pure.
It's okay, calm down.
Get the instant noodles. That one.
Are there any more instant noodles?
Ice cream.
Hey, what are you doing?
- What?
- Oh, no.
Let's go.
Hello, my fans!
This is Dong-hyun.
I'm at a supermarket,
and there's blood on the floor.
My gosh.
For all of you, I will risk everything
and make really fun content.
I love you, my fans!
Young lady, what are you doing there?
Young lady.
Be quiet.
People suddenly poured in.
They had weird eyes.
I got scared, so I was hiding here.
What about those infected people?
Did they go outside?
I don't know.
Let's get out of here.
Hurry.
There's blood.
Let's get out of here.
Where are the others?
I don't know.
Run!
- What?
- There are people in there.
Hey!
We can't just leave them here!
I mean, I'm coming with you.
Over here! Hurry!
What are you doing? Let's go.
Mister.
Go down to the first floor.
Why?
Sae-bom said you should come down
if she doesn't come back by 10.
Okay, I will.
You really saw it?
Yes, I did!
And why did they go out
when it's so dangerous?
What if they all come back infected?
You're right.
I can't open this door
unless our safety is assured.
Yes.
Yes, go ahead. Sure.
That old lady is just like me.
Open the door!
- Is anyone infected?
- Open the door!
Come closer. I have to check.
Open the door, now!
Why is there blood on your face?
Did you get bitten?
Open the door, now!
No!
I said, open the door!
- You got bitten, didn't you?
- Come on!
We're all fine! Open the door, now!
Open the door!
Go on.
No!
Open the door!
Smash it!
Please…
We're really going to smash it down!
Open it!
What's that sound?
- Open the door! Hey!
- The sound Min-ji made.
What are you trying to do with that…
I told you we only need
to persuade the couple downstairs.
Dead men tell no tales.
Corpses can't talk.
No!
Open the door, now!
The infected cannot come in here!
Open it, now!
Open the door, now!
I can't open it!
Open the door!
Hey, what's all this…
- Open the door!
- What are you doing?
Let go!
Hey!
Open the door!
Open the door, now!
- Open the door, now!
- Open the door!
Lady, hurry!
Open the door, now!
You!
- Who do you think you are…
- Stop that!
- Die!
- Don't do this!
What are you doing? Get in!
- Go away!
- Damn it!
- Come here!
- Please stop!
Honey, stop! Please!
- Come here!
- Stop it!
- Turn this thing off!
- What's wrong with you!
- Calm down, please!
- Let go!
Oh Joo-hyung did this.
What a shame.
That was a good chance.
What a waste.
What's with that look on your face?
I didn't do anything.
I did nothing wrong. What's the problem?
Oh Joo-hyung!
Did you bring my phone?
What the…
What?
What are you trying
to charge me with this time?
Are you crazy?
This blood is from outside.
Are you scared now?
Are you scared
that you might get infected now?
You asshole!
Yi-hyun!
Once the Internet starts to work again,
it will be a big hit!
Darn it.
Sorry, I was a bit agitated.
If it weren't for you,
all of us might've gotten infected.
Good job, Yi-hyun.
- The one responsible should repent!
- Repent!
- Take responsibility for the infected!
- Take responsibility!
- Protect the survivors!
- Protect!
- Give a definite answer on compensation!
- Give a definite answer!
Lieutenant Colonel,
an infected escaped from the apartments.
He's in serious condition.
Shall we take him back?
Take responsibility for the infected!
- Release him.
- What?
Release him, making it look like
a mistake, and let the protesters see him.
And suppress him quickly,
so no one would get hurt.
Lieutenant Colonel.
We should not let them pity the infected.
We must make them fear them
and want to avoid them.
That will buy us time
until the antibodies are developed.
All the residents here
are extremely anxious.
I want to buy that drug.
Yes, that's it!
If you think outside of the box,
you can get tons of ideas.
The situation will only get worse.
We must kick him out.
That's the only way we can survive.
- The ones who bought the drugs.
- The 15th floor.
So we wait
until the infected are all dead?
If you messed with Sae-bom,
I'm going to kill you.
Subtitle translation by: Hae-lim Lee